Something else is out there.
The Legend of Ochi is a family, fantasy,
adventure film directed by Isaiah Saxon.
In a remote village on the island of Carpathia, a shy farm girl named Yuri
is raised to fear an elusive animal species known as ochi.
But when Yuri discovers a wounded baby ochi has been left
behind, she escapes on a quest to bring him home.
Yuri, played by Helena Zengel.
Maxim, played by Willem Dafoe.
Dasha, played by Emily Watson.
Petro, played by Finn Wolfhard.
Ivan, played by Razvan Stoica.
Oleg, played by Carol Bors.
The Legend of Ochi () is a 2025 American fantasy adventure film written and directed by Isaiah Saxon in his
feature film debut and starring Helena Zengel, Finn Wolfhard, Emily Watson, and Willem Dafoe.
It tells the story of a farm girl on a fictional Black Sea island who discovers a wounded baby primate-like creature and works to return
it to its family while learning their language and avoiding a hunting party led by her father and her adopted brother.
It was released in the United States by A24 in limited theaters on
April 18, 2025 before a wide release on April 25.
The film was met with positive reviews.
The film explores themes of bite, forest, dysfunctional
family, creature, children's adventure.
The tone is lighthearted.